# 哈喽 大家好我是王刚
Hello everone, I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this video, I am going to share the process of
# 糖色的过程
Making caramelized sugar.
# 首先我们来了解有色糖和无色糖
Firstly, let’s have a look at colored sugars and colourless sugars.
# 有色糖大概有
Colored sugards include
# 片糖
Sliced cane sugar
# 红糖
Brown sugar
# 土冰糖
Matured rock sugar
# 无色糖大概有
Colourless sugars include
# 白砂糖
White granulated sugar
# 精炼冰糖
Refined rock sugar
# 其中冰糖又分精炼冰糖和土冰糖
Refined rock sugar and matured rock sugar are branched of rock sugar.
# 精炼冰糖的纯度高更透明且杂质非常少
Refined rock sugar has higher purity, it is transparent and has very little impurities.
# 因为颜色纯净下锅融化得也更快更好
Its purity allows it to melt faster while cooking,
# 所以比较适合炒糖色
and therefore, it is a good choice for making caramelized sugar.
# 土冰糖偏淡黄色略带蔗糖的原始甜香味
Matured rock sugar has pale-yellow appearance, it accompanied with the original flavor of cane sugar
# 它的优点是精炼次数少
With the advantage of less refinement,
# 营养成分保留得更多
It maintained more nutrients in either amount
# 更全面
and kinds.
# 但同时杂质也相对更多
On contrast, it has more impurities.
# 土冰糖比较适合熬粥
Matured rock sugar is better to be used when preparing congee,
# 泡茶
teas,
# 泡开水
hot water.
# 片糖的优点是方便储存不易回潮
Sliced cane sugar has the convinience in storage and hard to be damped,
# 相对比较硬
It is also more solid,
# 不容易化开适合广式糖水
hard to melt, so it’s suitable for making Cantonese sugar water
# 红糖的质量比较松软
Brown sugar is more soft, and
# 也是所有糖类中最容易吸收之一
It is one of the easiest absorbed sugar
# 其特点是不容易保存容易回潮
It is not easy to store and easily get damped
# 白砂糖炒制的糖色色泽不如冰糖红亮
Caramelized sugar made from white granulated sugar doesn’t looks as red and light as it made from rock sugar
# 最常见的作用就是烹饪时候的调味
While cooking, it is most commonly used as seasoning
# 在这里不建议大家用砂糖炒制糖色
Therefore, it is not a good idea to make caramelized sugar from granulated sugar
# 下一步开始制作
Then, let’s start
# 首先我们选择适量的精炼冰糖敲碎备用
We firstly break suitable amount of refined rock sugar for preparation
# 这一步的目的是让冰糖在炒制的时候更快的溶解
This aimed to help melting the sugar while cooking
# 然后加入和冰糖等量的清水
Then add water with the same amount as sugar
# 新手操作建议糖和水的比例增加到1:1.2
If you are new for this, the sugar to water ratio could be 1:1.2
# 再加入适量的植物油
Add proper amount of vegetable oil
# 加植物油可以提升炒糖色的时候的温度
Vegetavle oil could rise the temperature while stiring the caramelized sugar
# 下一步开始操作
Next, we start to cook
# 首先我们开中小火把调好的糖水下锅
Firstly, we turn on the cooking bench at medium level, and pour the sugar water into the pot
# 糖水下锅之后烧开转小火边搅边观察糖的变化
After boiled, turn the cooking bench to low level and pay attention to the change in sugar
# 糖浆充分融化之后会起比较大的气泡
If sugar melt completely, there would be big bubbles
# 然后继续熬至水分蒸发
Then continue cooking until water evaporated
# 水分蒸发之后气泡变小
The bubble will be smaller after evaporation
# 即可以制作挂霜的菜品
Then it could be used for preparing dishes that need guashuang
# 继续熬制糖浆变成香油色的时候
If continue cooking until the syrup has a similar color to sesame oil
# 也就是糖浆逐渐变成淡黄色之后
in other word, after syrup gradually changed to pale-yellow,
# 又马上可以进入拔丝菜品的状态
It could be used for preparing dishes that need hot candied
# 好 我们继续往下制作
Ok, let’s continue.
# 再接着糖浆的黄色会加深
The color of syrup will be depper
# 这个时候的糖
At this time,
# 非常适合做冰糖葫芦
It is best to be used to make bingtanghulu,
# 冰糖李子等等
Bingtanglizi, and etc.
# 继续开火
Let’s keep cooking
# 略等十秒钟之后会变成初级枣红色
It would changed to purplish red after about ten seconds
# 如果此时加入开水的话
If we add water at this time
# 就是略带甜味的糖色
It is the caramelized sugar that is slightly sweet
# 行业之中称为嫩汁
We call it nengzhi
# 初级变色之后将锅离火
Taking the pot away from the cooking bench after it change color
# 利用余温将嫩汁顶呈深枣色
Utilize the tempeture left and waite the top of nengzhi change to deep-purplish red
# 深枣色之后再加入糖浆自身两倍的开水
Then add water as twice amont on volumn as syrup
# 同学们切记不能用冷水
Please do not use cold water
# 冷水容易让高温的糖浆炸裂伤人
Since cold water will cause the syrup crack and possibly hurt people
# 也容易让糖色的颜色不融合导致分层
It may also cause the distinct color of caramelized sugar, and lead to hierarchical appearance
# 加入开水之后也要继续熬煮一分钟
Waiting one more nimute after adding the water
# 最终的糖色无味
The final caramelized sugar is tasteless
# 颜色红亮
Has bright red color
# 非常适合添加到卤味和红烧当中
And very suitable to be added into master stock
# 初次制作卤味的时候糖色需要慢慢的添加
While first time making the master stock, caramelized should be gradually added
# 直到颜色适合之后即可
Until the color looks fine
# 然后再加入配制好的卤料包和调味料
Then, add premade halogen package and seasoning
# 用糖色调色的卤水
Using the master stock that was mixed with caramelized sugar
# 需要注意的是
Please notice that
# 卤制的成品在出锅之后需要刷上一层油保色
The stewed product should be brushed over with oil
# 否则糖色很容易经过时间的氧化变黑
Or caramelized sugar will easily get dark since the oxidation
# 下面开始技术总结
Followings are technicial summary
# 糖水过程的质变
The process of qualitative change of sugar
# 第一水分蒸发之后
Firstly, after evaporation
# 气泡变小是挂霜
Small bubbles implies guashuang is available
# 同学们挂霜也就是水分蒸发完的时候关火
If performing guashuang, turn off the cooking bench after completely evaporation
# 下入原材料翻炒至冷却
Add ingredients and keep stiring until cooled
# 此做法称为挂霜
Whis is so called guashuang
# 同学们切记
Please remember
# 一定要关火炒到糖浆冷却
We must turn off the cooking bench and keep stiring until syrup is cooled,
# 凝固硬化
solidated
# 第二糖浆变黄是拔丝
Secondly, hot candied is prepared when syrup become yellow
# 拔丝原料下锅之前必须再加入少许的底油
Add few oil before adding the food ingredients
# 这一步的目的是让糖丝能够拉得更长
This aimmed to make sugar filaments as long as possible
# 成菜冷却之后且不容易粘连成一坨
and ingradients won’t glue up
# 第三
Thirdly,
# 糖浆颜色变深之后可以挂糖制作
After the color of syrup become deeper, it could be used to make sugar coating
# 琥珀核桃
Amber walnut
# 冰糖葫芦
bingtanghulu
# 冰糖李子等等
Bingtanglizi and etc.
# 同学们切记
Please remember
# 糖浆必须有热度才能挂得更薄
Thinner sugar coating can only be obtained by using hot syrup
# 糖浆温度下降的时候则越厚
The coating will be whicker if the temperature of syrup drop
# 糖色的质变技术总结完毕
This is the end of qualitative change od sugar technicial summary.